



PRINCIPAL GEOSPATIAL ENGINEER TS/SCI POLYGRAPH

703-915-2656

Nikkicruzjackson@gmail.com

Pairfax Station, VA

in <u>nikki-jackson-hebson</u>

Portfolio Portfolio

EDUCATION

MASTER OF SCIENCE, GIS DEVELOPMENT - 4.0 University of Wisconsin – Madison 2019 – 2021

GRADUATE CERTIFICATE, GEOSPATIAL INTELLIGENCE ANALYTICS - 4.0

The Pennsylvania State University 2018

BACHELOR OF ARTS, GEOGRAPHY, GIS - 3.7

George Mason University 2007 - 2010

KEY SKILLS

GIS & Web Map Programming SQL Query & Manipulation
Data Collection & Conversion

Visualization

3D Modeling

Intelligence Analytics

Cartography & Graphic Design

Database Administration

Project Management

Team Leadership

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Geospatial Engineer with 13 years of GIS and Cartography experience supporting Defense and Intelligence Agencies by applying GIS scripting, mapping, modeling, analysis, and database management principals. Dedicated professional that thrives in demanding environments and is committed to continuing education to promote mission success. Education includes a Bachelor of Arts in Geography and GIS, a Graduate Certificate of Geospatial Intelligence Analytics, and a Master of Science focused in GIS Development and Web Map Programming.

EXPERIENCE

PRINCIPAL GEOSPATIAL ENGINEER

SAIC, Chantilly, VA | May 2016 - Present

Support Intelligence Customer by producing geospatial tools, analysis, cartography, and graphics in a quick turnaround operational environment.

- Managing the creation and maintenance of worldwide geospatial databases for use in operational planning, intelligence products, and analysis.
- Participation in all phases of project life cycle: analysis, design, develop, test, debug, deploy, maintain, and update.
- Apply specialized knowledge of spatial data formats and storage to develop advanced mapping capabilities.

SENIOR GEOSPATIAL ANALYST

Courage Services, Arlington, VA | July 2015 - May 2016

Supported Foundation GEOINT Content Management (FGCM) task as a Senior Geospatial Analyst Project Lead.

- Responsible for transferring Statement of Work (SOW) into Standard Operation Procedures (SOPs) for team members to ensure tasks are completed to specification and in the most efficient way possible.
- Day to day involvement with all technical aspects of the project including DVOF, GAIT, Batch Checks, Imagery Prep, Metadata, and Quality Control using Data Reviewer and Production specific toolsets.
- Collaborating with Leadership Team to write proposals and create budgets for upcoming and proposed projects.

GEOSPATIAL ANALYST

MDA Information Systems, VA | January 2015 - July 2015

Supported Intelligence Customer by providing research and producing geospatial analysis and cartography in a fast-paced operational environment.

- Research, collect, integrate, and analyze a variety of spatially enabled intelligence to characterize events, discover, relations, and identify patterns.
- Generate daily reports incorporating signals intelligence information to disseminate to operations support within the area of responsibility.
- Collaborate with USMIL, NSA, NGA, and numerous other Intelligence
 Community entities during the collection, research, analysis, and product generation process.

EXPERTISE

ESRI ArcGIS Pro & Desktop

Adobe Illustrator

MAPublisher

Google Earth

PostgreSQL

Python

Javascript

HTML5

CSS

Leaflet

D3

IntelliJ

Github

Atom

Tomcat

AWS

AutoCAD

ACHIEVEMENT

AWARDED OUTSTANDING UNDERGRADUATE STUDENT IN GEOGRAPHY

George Mason University 2010 - Fairfax, VA

HONOR GRADUATE MAGNA CUM LAUDE

George Mason University 2010 - Fairfax, VA

EXPERIENCE - CONTINUED -

GEOSPATIAL ANALYST

Leidos (formally SAIC), Reston, VA | February 2014 - January 2015

- Produced long and short-term geospatial targeting packages based on customer requests.
- Created interactive geospatial products in Google Earth with custom requested symbology.
- Maintained customer collection of geospatial products through precise cataloging processes.
- Supported customer and contractor Intelligence Analysts with on-site technical geospatial training with emphasis on tradecraft and innovative methodologies.

GIS ANALYST

SAIC, Chantilly, VA | February 2010 - February 2014

- Extracted vector data for NGA standard products based on commercial imagery and digital elevation model data in an ArcSDE environment.
- Managed, updated, and created geodatabases in ESRI ArcGIS Desktop.
- Supported cartographic production of NGA standard products.
- Georeferenced historic maps using native coordinate systems to prepare for vector extraction.
- Trained fellow analysts on standard operating procedures of a geospatial production environment.
- Performed as a final quality control analyst for several project phases.

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

AWS CLOUD PRACTITIONER CERTIFICATION
Amazon Web Services
August 2020